# YAN BONNEL

JAVA AND ANDROID DEVELOPER

ybonnel@gmail.com https://github.com/ybonnel Twitter:@ybonnel

# Profile

Developer with 7 years experience on Java and more recently (about 2 years) on native Android development.

Skills

Java

I work with java for 7 years, I like very much community around Java, go to JUG, Devoxx, ... Android

I develop on Android for 2 years on personnal projects. HTML<sub>5</sub>

I'm interested in new HTML technologies (like JQuery, Angular.js, JQuery Mobile, Twitter bootstrap). Continuous delivery

I like to automate everything and have a real continuous delivery.

**Technical** 

Java	Hibernate	HTML5	Jenkins
JEE	Play framework	CSS	Sonar
Spring	Android	Javascript/JQuery	Maven

Experience

Sopra Group Software Architect

02/2008 - now

Transversal technical leader on 1 Java applications, team of 30 people (from 07/2013 to now)

Applications in charge of housing demand in France.

### Functions:

• Technical expert: support for all developers.

### Technologies:

- Java
- Maven
- Spring
- Struts
- Axis
- Postgresql
- Tomcat
- SVN

Transversal technical leader on 4 Java applications, team of 30 people (from 05/2012 to 06/2013)

Applications in charge of network activation for a french mobile operator.

New application management contract with reversibility.

Work in team with Indian people.

### Functions :

- Continuous delivery: define build and install processes with Jenkins for all applications.
- Technical expert: support for all developers.
- $\circ~$  Help to resolve issues on multiple environments.
- Realization of a Web portal for developers (Play framework).

### Technologies:

- Java
- Ant
- Jboss
- Oracle

- Unix
- Jenkins
- · Play Framework
- SVN

### Technical leader on 2 Java applications, team of 100 to 200 people (02/2008 - 04-2012)

Redisign project of the core system for a french mobile operator.

This project covers from order to billing through a catalog for the offers' referential.

#### Functions:

- Bench of Cameleon Software (used for the catalog offers) 5 months
  - Use of Load Runner.
  - Development of a webservice layer to abstract Cameleon (Jboss WS).
- Writing functionnal specifications for the catalog offers 6 months.
- Technical leader on the catalog offers, 5 to 10 developers 1 year
  - Webservices (JbossWS),
  - Hibernate,
  - Continuous integration (Maven, Hudson, Sonar).
- Technical leader on a taking order system, 10 to 30 developers more than 2 years
  - Webservices (CXF),
  - Spring core, JPA, Hibernate,
  - Continuous integration (Maven, Jenkins, Sonar),
  - Installation and integration of Gerrit (software to help in code revue),
  - Realization of a Web portal for developers (Play Framework).

### Technologies:

- o Java,
- · Spring core,
- o Jboss,
- · Hibernate, JPA,
- Webservices (JbossWS and CXF),
- o Oracle,
- o Unix,
- o Maven,
- o Jenkins,
- Play Framework,
- SVN,
- Git (used for Web portal).

# Sopra Group

11/2007 - 01/2008

Junior Software Architect

# Create an UI to manage documents (team of 5 people)

Application in charge of document management for all exploitation documents.

### Functions:

- Participation in the pre-study for realization.
- Creation of the base code for the development.

### Technologies:

- Java/JEE,
- Struts,
- Hibernate,
- SVN.

# Sopra Group

07/2006 - 10/2007

#### used by users.

### Functions:

- C++ developments under Unix for an activation system.
- JEE developments for an administration interface.
- Java developments under Windows for a forecasting system radio coverage.
- $\circ~$  Participation in specifications and testing for these applications.

### Technologies:

- o C++,
- o Unix/Shell,
- Java/JEE,
- o Struts,
- PVCS Version Manager,
- VBScript.

# Sopra Group

02/2006 - 06/2006

### Developer

#### Final-year internship

Participation in developing an activation system for a french mobile operator.

- C++ developments under Unix (HP UX),
- Unix Scripting (KSH).

# Off-work projects

# Community

2012 - now

Part in organisation of multiple conferences.

- Breizhcamp
- Codeurs en Seine

### Speaker

- o Breizhcamp: "Une application Web simple en Java, c'est possible"
- NormandyJUG

## SimpleWeb4j github/SimpleWeb4j

03/2013 - now

Small java framework to create web application based on angularjs and REST services.

# "Transports Rennes" and "Transports Bordeaux" github/TransportsRennes

08/2010 - now

<u>Transports Rennes on Google Play</u> <u>Transports Bordeaux on Google Play</u>

Android applications for public transportation of Rennes and Bordeaux.

Use of Open-Data for thess two cities.

### Some statistics :

- Transports Rennes' downloads: more than 19 000,
- Transports Rennes' comments: more than 500 ratings with 4.642/5 average,
- Transports Bordeaux' downloads: more than 18 000,
- Transports Bordeaux' comments: more than 250 ratings with 4.627/5 average,
- Source code: more than 30 000 LOC (Project on ohloh).

# CsvEngine github/CsvEngine

05/2011 - now

Small java framework based on annotations used to parse and write CSV files.

## <u>github/TransportsRouen</u> <u>transports-rouen.appspot.com</u>

Small mobile web app for public bikes in Rouen. Used to test JQuery Mobile technology.

# BreizhCamp github/breizhjug

2011 - now

Participation in all developments for web applications used by BreizhCamp. BreizhCamp is a two-day conference organized by Rennes' JUG.

## Education

# University of La Rochelle (France)

2000 - 2006

Master in computer sciences (specialty: pattern recognition and image processing).

Yan Bonnel — <u>vbonnel@gmail.com</u>